About Ascendion

Ascendion is a leader in AI-powered software engineering, helping businesses innovate faster, smarter, and with greater impact. We partner with Global 2000 clients across North America, UK, Europe, and APAC to solve complex challenges in data, experience design, software product engineering, and workforce transformation. Powered by expert engineers, thousands of AI agents, and our Engineering to the Power of AI™ (EngineeringAI) method, we deliver measurable outcomes that build trust, unlock value, and accelerate growth. Learn more at ascendion.com

Ascendion | Engineering to elevate life

We have a culture built on opportunity, inclusion, and a spirit of partnership. Come, change the world with us:

 Build the coolest tech for world’s leading brands
 Solve complex problems – and learn new skills
 Experience the power of transforming digital engineering for Fortune 500 clients
 Master your craft with leading training programs and hands-on experience

Experience a community of change makers!

Join a culture of high-performing innovators with endless ideas and a passion for tech. Our culture is the fabric of our company, and it is what makes us unique and diverse. The way we share ideas, learning, experiences, successes, and joy allows everyone to be their best at Ascendion.

Responsibilities

Design, develop, and maintain enterprise-grade applications using Java and Spring Boot.
Build and enhance Microservices-based architectures for scalable and resilient systems.
Develop, integrate, and optimize RESTful APIs and web services.
Work with SQL and NoSQL databases to design efficient data models and optimize performance.
Implement secure, high-performing, and reusable application components.
Collaborate with product owners, architects, QA teams, and other stakeholders throughout the software development lifecycle.
Participate in code reviews, technical discussions, and architectural decision-making.
Troubleshoot production issues and drive performance tuning and application optimization.
Ensure adherence to coding standards, security best practices, and software development methodologies.
Contribute to CI/CD pipelines and DevOps initiatives.